Thiago William da Silva Brito - Frontend developer

Mobile: +353 0830700040 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/thiago-william/

E-mail: Thiago.will.silva@gmail.com

Languages: Portuguese (Native) - English (pre-intermediate)

Blog: thiagowilliam.com.br

Github: thiagowilliam.github.io

Cover Letter

My name is Thiago william, I am Brazilian and I am currently living in Ireland where I study English through an exchange. I am a frontend programmer and have been programming for over 8 years, always learning new technologies.

I started working only with the graphic part of web projects. Planning and creating interfaces for websites and web systems with Photoshop. As soon as I graduated in graphic design, I decided to improve myself in the front-end area, which I fell in love with HTML, CSS and JS.

As a developer, I directed my career towards web and mobile systems using Javascript technologies, considering the evolution of several frameworks such as NodeJS, VueJS, ReactJS, React Native and Ionic.

I quickly learn new technologies, and also the sector-specific concepts that ask me to work. I love to code and provide a great experience for users. Perform a project from start to finish is a pleasure, Seeking to deliver to the user a product that helps him to have efficient solutions, keeping the user interface intuitive.

In the penultimate company I worked for 6 years I started working as a web designer, I was promoted to frontend developer and over time I came to the supervisory position, leading a team of 6 people. We develop incredible projects like http://consorcios.cnm.org.br/. This is an online platform that aims to register and present information about existing public consortia in Brazil. We used the Vue.JS Framework, consuming data from an APIRest to feed a map that showed the main information on the platform.

I wanted an experience with mobile platforms, that's when I had the opportunity to join Monumenta's development team. Despite the short passage, I participated in the development of the MyVo Application. Which is a photovoltaic energy generation and management platform. It was an incredible experience working with React Native.

I recently felt the need to learn English because I wanted to participate in international events, learn technologies more quickly and be able to communicate better with other programmers. That's why I decided to do this exchange where I also hope to have an international experience.

In my free time: I like to run around the park and spend time with my family. I participate in conferences, online courses and help the javascript community by answering questions and contributing to open source projects.

Thiago William da Silva Brito - Frontend developer

Mobile: +353 0830700040 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/thiago-william/

E-mail: Thiago.will.silva@gmail.com Blog: thiagowilliam.com.br Languages: Portuguese (Native) - English (pre-intermediate) Github: thiagowilliam.github.io

Career Summary

I love to code and provide a great experience for users. I have been programming for over 8 years, always learning new technologies. The web is incredible and I fall in love more and more with this profession.

IT Skills Overview

I can program in	Html and template languages, responsive design(Mobile First), Css(Sass and Stylus), Css Frameworks (Bootstrap and Bulma), Javascript, ReactJS/Redux/Flux, React Native, NodeJs, Git
Already worked with	JavaScript, ReactJS, React Native, Node.JS

Education

2016 - 2018	UNOPAR – EAD (Postgraduate studies) Brasilia, Brazil Course: technologies for web application	This course focuses on Develop web application analysis skills.
2010 - 2012	<u>University paulista</u> Brasilia, Brazil Course: graphic design	This course focuses on UX Design and UI Design. Visual creation of websites, blogs, banners for the internet

Employment History

Analyst Frontend - 07/2019 - 11/2019

Monumenta Comunicação e Estratégias Sociais - Brasília, Brazil (monumenta.com.br/) - Digital Agency. Responsibilities:

- √ Requirements Survey and Analysis
- ✓ Development of Frontend Systems for Web and Mobile in JavaScript (ReactJS and React Native)
- √ Versioning using GIT
- √ API REST data consumption.

Frontend Developer - 04/2013 - 07/2019

CNM (Confederação Nacional de Municípios) - Brasilia, Brazil (www.cnm.org.br/).

Responsibilities:

- ✓ Supervisor and Team Manager in the Development Sector.
- ✓ Preparation of performance reports
- √ Requirements Survey and Analysis.
- ✓ Development of Frontend Systems for Web in JavaScript (VueJs, jQuery, D3.js, Highcharts, NodeJs).
- √ Versioning using GIT.
- ✓ API REST data consumption.

<u>Instructor of Information Technology courses - 02/2013 - 01/2014</u>

SENAC - Brasília, Brazil (https://www.senac.br/)

Responsibilities:

- ✓ Planning classes for web design courses.
- ✓ Teach students the best practices and the latest technologies

Digital interface design and Frontend developer - 04/2012 - 04/2013

Plano Digital Comunicação - Brasília, Brazil - Digital Agency

Responsibilities:

- ✓ Developed new systems and tools. Maintained and migrated legacy systems.
- ✓ Digital structure and planning.
- ✓ creation and implementation of websites, banner, e-mail marketing using HTML, CSS and JavaScript(Jquery).

Web Designer - 08/2010 - 04/2012

Artmix Web - Brasília, Brazil - Digital Agency

Responsibilities:

- \checkmark Development and creation of websites and web banners.
- ✓ Design UX and Design UI.